<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creating and configuring a Plate Layout">
  
  <intro>
    <description>
	    This tutorial explains how a Plate Layout with markers and calculation 
	    functions are created. A Plate Layout defines which wells are used for 
	    controls, blanks or dilution series. It also defines the calculation 
	    functions applied on the raw values in order to reach for example SI%. 
    </description>
  </intro>
  
  <item title="Show the Brunn View" skip="true">
    <description>
	    All things stored in the Brunn database can be viewed using the Brunn 
	    view. In order to show this view click 
	    <b>Window -> Show View -> Other...</b> and choose Brunn Explorer view in
	    the Brunn category.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Log In" skip="true">
    <description>
        In order to access what is stored in the Brunn database you need to 
        sign in with your username and password. This can be done by right 
        clicking in the Brunn view where it says "Not Logged In" and select 
        <b>Log In</b> or by <b>File -> Log In</b>.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Create the Plate Layout">
    <description>
	    Right click on Plate Layouts or a sub folder to Plate Layouts in the 
	    Brunn view and select <b>Create Plate Layout</b>. In the dialog that 
	    pops up give your new Plate Layout a name and choose a Plate Type.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Open the new Plate Layout in the Plate Layout editor">
    <description>
        In order to place well markers and enter calculation functions the 
        Plate Layout needs to be opened in an editor. Double click the new 
        Plate Layout in the Brunn View. (It should be created now in the folder 
        you right clicked in the previous step)
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Place Markers">
    <description>
        The well markers signal what the well is to be used for. There are 
        5 different sort of markers. <br/>
        <b>P</b>: Positive Control <br/>
        <b>C</b>: Control <br/>       
        <b>Mx</b>: Substance marker. The first created will be M1 then M2 
                   and so on. One marker signifies one substance. <br/>
        <b>B</b>: Blank. <br/>
        In order to place markers, select some wells and right click and choose 
        what marker to add. (One M1 symbolizes one substance, so to make a 
        dilution serie for a substance mark a line of wells with the same M 
        marker.)
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Creating Plate Functions">
    <description>
    Plate Functions are values calculated for the plate. For example the average
    of all controls would be a plate function. While the markers where added a 
    couple of standard Plate Functions where automagicly generated. More can be 
    added by right clicking in the Plate Functions table in the lower part of 
    the editor and choosing <b>Add Function</b>. <br/>
    The following functions can be of use when writing Plate Functions: stddev, 
    avg, and sum. They can be called either like stddev(A1:B2) or 
    stddev(A1, A2, B1, B2).
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Creating Well Functions">
    <description>
      Well functions are used for calculating well specific like for example
      SI%. To add an SI% well function to a couple of wells do like this: <br/>
      <b>*</b> Select the wells that should have the new Well function <br/>
      <b>*</b> Make sure the bottom part of the editor shows 
               Well functions. <br/>
      <b>*</b> Right click and choose <b>Add function</b> <br/>
      The same functions available when writing Plate Functions are available 
      for Well functions. In order to get the raw value of the well just write 
      well. <br/>
      An SI% functions can look something like this: <br/>
      100 * ( well - AVG_AllBlanks() ) / ( AVG_C1() - AVG_AllBlanks() ) <br/>
      (Note that the SI% function for all wells using the same control can be 
      made at the same time)
    </description>
  </item>
    
</cheatsheet>