<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creating and configuring a Master Plate">
  
  <intro>
    <description>
      This tutorial explains how a Plate is created and how results are
      imported and connected with that plate. It also explains how the results 
      can be examined.
    </description>
  </intro>
  
  <item title="Show the Brunn View" skip="true">
    <description>
      All things stored in the Brunn database can be viewed using the Brunn 
      view. In order to show this view click 
      <b>Window -> Show View -> Other...</b> and choose Brunn Explorer view in
      the Brunn category.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Log In" skip="true">
    <description>
      In order to access what is stored in the Brunn database you need to 
      sign in with your username and password. This can be done by right 
      clicking in the Brunn view where it says "Not Logged In" and select 
      <b>Log In</b> or by <b>File -> Log In</b>.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Create Plate">
    <description>
      Right click on Plates or a sub folder to Plates in the Brunn view and 
      select <b>Create Plate</b>. In the dialog that
      pops up give your new Plate a name, choose a Master Plate to base 
      it on, either a cell sample or a patient sample and enter the plates 
      barcode which will be used when importing data for it.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Opening the Import Results Wizard">
    <description>
      Results are imported into Brunn by clicking 
      <b>Import Results from File</b> in the menu for the Brunn View. To open 
      this menu click the little triangle in the upper right corner of the 
      Brunn Explorer view.  
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Choosing Results File">
    <description>
      In the first wizard page click <B>Browse</B> and locate the file to 
      import and click <B>OK</B>. Brunn supports imports from three 
      different file formats. Two of them are file formats of files generated 
      by machines and the third one is CSV files.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Select Plates to Import">
    <description>
        The next wizard page looks a bit different depending on what file was 
        used. If the file contained barcodes makes sure that the plate to be
        imported really exists in the database and check the box next to it to 
        import it when Finish is clicked. However if the file does not contain 
        that barcode or if the barcode reader has failed to read the barcode the
        barcode must be added manually. Select the row representing the plate to
        be imported and right click and choose <b>Change barcode</b>. Once the 
        wizard page reports that the plate with the given barcode exists in the 
        database results can be imported for it.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Opening the Plate Editor to View Results">
    <description>
      When data has been imported for a plate it can be viewed using the Plate 
      editor. Locate the plate in the Brunn Explorer and doubleclick it to open 
      it in the Plate Editor.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The Overview tab in the Plate Editor">
    <description>
      The overview tab shows the values for the plate as they are organized on 
      the actual plate. In the right end there is a list of all markers and 
      another one of all plate functions. Selecting a marker will select the 
      cells corresponding to the wells with that marker. At the bottom of the 
      editor there is a combo box for showing different well functions in the 
      big table and to the right there is a button for marking selected wells
      as outliers. The results can be copied (to be pasted in for example Excel)
      by clicking the <b>Copy data to Clipboard</b> button.<br/>
      To switch to the Summary tab click <b>Summary</b> in the bottom left 
      corner of the editor.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The Summary tab in the Plate Editor">
    <description>
      The Summary tab shows all well functions for all wells and som more info. 
      Wells can be marked as outliers by selecting the row corresponding to a 
      well and clicking the <b>Mark as outlier</b> button in the bottom part of 
      the editor.The table can be copied (to be pasted in for example Excel) by
      clicking the <b>Copy Table to Clipboard</b> button. <br/>
      To switch to the Average tab click <b>Average</b> in the bottom left 
      corner of the editor.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The Average tab in the Plate Editor">
    <description>
      The Average tab shows a similar table to the Summary tab but it has 
      mashed together all replicates and shows the averages for them. <br/>
      To switch to the IC50 tab click <b>IC50</b> in the bottom left corner of 
      the editor.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The IC50 tab in the Plate Editor">
    <description>
      This tab shows the estimated IC50 values for the compounds. <br/>
      To switch to the report tab click <b>Report</b> in the bottom left corner 
      of the editor. <br/>
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The Report tab in the Plate Editor">
    <description>
      The report tab contains a report with plots and numbers. It can be 
      exported in multiple formats and hopefully printed from one of those 
      exported formats. To export, click the export icon (fourth from the left) 
      and choose a format and export.
    </description>
  </item>
</cheatsheet>