<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creating and configuring a Master Plate">
  
  <intro>
    <description>
      This tutorial explains how a Master Plate is created. A Master Plate 
      defines which compounds and with what concentration the wells contains.
    </description>
  </intro>
  
  <item title="Show the Brunn View" skip="true">
    <description>
      All things stored in the Brunn database can be viewed using the Brunn 
      view. In order to show this view click 
      <b>Window -> Show View -> Other...</b> and choose Brunn Explorer view in
      the Brunn category.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Log In" skip="true">
    <description>
      In order to access what is stored in the Brunn database you need to 
      sign in with your username and password. This can be done by right 
      clicking in the Brunn view where it says "Not Logged In" and select 
      <b>Log In</b> or by <b>File -> Log In</b>.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Create the Master Plate">
    <description>
      Right click on Master Plate or a sub folder to Master Plates in the 
      Brunn view and select <b>Create Master Plate</b>. In the dialog that 
      pops up choose a Plate Layout to base your Master Plate on, give the 
      number of plates in the batch and give your new Master Plate a name.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Create Compounds" skip="true">
    <description>
      Before adding compounds to the Master Plate, some compounds might need 
      to be created. Compounds are created in the same way as Master Plates. 
      Right click the Compounds folder or any of it's subfolders and select 
      <b>Create Compound</b>. Give it a name and a molecular weight if 
      applicable. Checking the "Keep creating more compunds" box opens a new 
      instance of the dialog ready to create another compound when <b>OK</b> 
      is clicked.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Open the new Master Plate in the Master Plate Editor">
    <description>
      In order to place compounds on the Master Plate it needs to be opened 
      in an editor. Double click the new Master Plate in the Brunn View. (It 
      should be created by now in the folder you right clicked in the previous 
      step)
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Add Compounds to the Master Plate">
	<description>
	  Compounds are added by dragging them from the Brunn Explorer view to one
	  of the list of markers in the bottom part of the editor. This brings up a 
	  dialog where dilutions series can be created. When <b>OK</b> is clicked in 
	  this dialog the compound is added to all wells with that marker.
	</description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Edit Compound Concentrations on the Master Plate" skip="true">
    <description>
      If the desired concentrations could not be achieved using the dialog, the 
      concentration of a compound in a well can be changed by double clicking 
      and editing the value in a dialog.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="The Report">
    <description>
      Once all markers have been connected to a compound, a report of the master 
      plate can be viewed. Change to the report tab by clicking <b>Report</b> in 
      the bottom left corner of the editor. The report can be exported to PDF by
      clicking the <b>Export Report</b> icon (fourth from left) and choose PDF 
      as export format. Also recommended is to tick the fit to page box. The 
      exported pdf will be opened in some program depending on how the local 
      computer is set up and can hopefully be printed from that program. (It is
      alos possible to export to as a .doc file and open it in Microsoft Word).
    </description>
  </item>

</cheatsheet>